CAREER SUMMARY

Project Manager / Engineer with over 18 years of overall experience in the profession of which 14 years in UAE & Qatar and rest in India. Proven track record of handling projects, interacting and coordinating with clients and contractors. Involved in designing of Gas systems, project management and site supervision for projects from Commercial, Industrial, Hotels and Palace building.

Worked as Project co-ordinator for PANAMA Godavari Wind Farm for installation of 40Nos. 2MW WTG (Gamesa) at Mirkala Site, Georai - Beed (Marathwada), Maharashtra.

Able to work in a fast paced environment with tight deadlines. Team player with good communication, interpersonal and presentation skills.

EDUCATION

<u>Diploma in Tool and Die Making, Nettur Technical Training Foundation (NTTF) Karnataka, India</u>

- Nettur Technical Training Foundation, An ISO 9001 Training Institution Specialized College with collaboration of India and Switzerland was established in 1964 registered with Director of Technical Education, Karnataka & recognized by Central Government of India.
 - Concentration: 5 years Diploma in Tool & Die making involving Tool & Mould Design, Drawings, Estimation & Costing, Material Technology, Machining and Tool Assembly, Inspection and Quality Control.

Business Information Technology (HND, UK).

DUBAI POLYTECHNIC (Dubai chamber of Commerce) Completed 7 Modules in 2000

Passed the test and possess Technician Card from Dubai Civil Defence for Central Gas systems.

Training in "Negotiation Skills" module in "Business Skills Modular Training Program" at ENOC (Emirates National Oil Co) / EPPCO Learning & Development Centre.

LANGUAGES

Good in spoken and written English & native Indian Languages like Hindi, Kannada, Marathi.

EMPLOYMENT RECORD

Period	Employer	Position
Jan 2014 – June 2014	GR Green Life Energy Private	Project Co-ordinator
	Ltd	
April 2009 to 2013	Religas Systems Co., India	Proprietor
June 2007 – April 2008	JAMCO W.L.L,	Manager
	Oil & Gas Division	
	Doha, Qatar	
January 1995 – May 2007	Cylingas Company Ltd LLC	Project Engineer
	(Member of Emirates National	
	Oil Co ENOC Group of	
	Companies), Dubai	
September 1993 - August 1994	Khodiyar Engineering Works	Trainee
	Mumbai, India	

GR Greenlife Energy Pvt Ltd, Pune India (Jan 2014 till June 2014).

Worked as Project co-ordinator with Project Execution team for Wind Turbine Development / installation for Panama Godavari Wind Farms with 40Nos. 2MW WTG at Mirkala Site, Beed (Marathwada), Maharashtra.

Work involves Co-ordination between Client & WTG component manufacturer (GAMESA) and inter department HOD's Land, Civil / Road & Electrical, inolving planning schedules, DPRs and deliveries of materials MCC / WCC and readiness of land to accommodate WTG Equipments.

Religas Systems Co, India (June 2008 to 2012)

Religas Systems Co is the distributor for Pergoraro Technologies, Italy

Propreitor

Proposing and enhancing optimal usage of LP Gas in existing and new set ups using advanced Technologies and Equipments.

Projects worked on:

- Proposed & Designed LP Gas system with LOT Cylinders with Vaporiser for
 - IFB, Bangalore.
 - Bhoruka Aluminium, Mysore.
 - Zircast, Bangalore.

JAMCO W.L.L, Oil and Gas Division, Doha, Qatar (June 2007 to April 2008)

Owned by members of Ruler family, Jamco is prominent suppliers of surfacing products like Tiles and ceramics, Kitchen Equipments for Government buildings, palaces, schools, residential compounds etc. It set up a new division for Oil & Gas services in 2007 to cater the needs of several Industrial, Commercial & Residential projects.

Project Manager

As approved by WOQOD / Qatar Fuel, was handed responsibility of Marketing & Sales in addition to project management, designing, estimation, planning, execution & coordinating with the team members, contractors and site supervision.

Forecasting market requirements, Market survey, Inventory Checks, Presentation to the Clients, Enhancing product knowledge of the Customers, propose new concepts for business development.

Involved In:

- 1 Setting up the new Oil & Gas Division with man power recruitment.
- 2 Joint Venture with overseas company Pegoraro Technologies, Italy.
- 3 Obtaining necessary approvals from WOQOD.
- 4 Tendering for the Pearl Project.
- 5 Tendering for Auto Gas pilot project for WOQOD.
- 6 Assisting consultants like Qatar Design Consortium, RMJM & also WOQOD for providing necessary information and system descriptions for Bulk Storage System

Cylingas Company LLC. Al Quoz, Dubai, UAE (Jan 1995 to May 2007)

Cylingas Company LLC was established on 28 April 1974 by a decree of the late ruler of Dubai His Highness Sheikh Rashid Bin Saeed Al Maktoum and is now a part of the multi-disciplined Dubai Government owned Emirates National Oil Company Ltd (ENOC) LLC.

Project Engineer (E & C/ Sales Division)

Responsibilities included project management, designing and execution of gas systems for Industrial Complex, Resorts, Hotels, Mass Production Kitchens, estimation, planning, execution, coordination with team members, client & contractors and site supervision.

Assist General Manager in making management reports, cash flow & analysis of actual job cost v/s estimated cost.

Obtaining necessary approvals from Local Authorities for the design & drawings and installations.

Marketing & Sales. Forecasting market requirements, Expected jobs, Market survey, Inventory Checks, Presentation to the Clients, Enhancing product knowledge of the Customers, propose new concepts for business development.

Marketing, promoting and implementing LPG Equipments / products manufactured by ECII- Rego, USA, Algas SDI, USA, Suregas S.Africa (for Gas Detection System) for existing and new projects. for which M/s Cylingas Co LLC, Dubai were distributors for GCC countries.

Sourcing / procurement of materials for the LP Gas installation, follow-ups with the supplier (both Inland & Overseas), and sourcing new overseas suppliers. Main suppliers like Blackmere Pumps, USA, Corken Compressors, USA, Fisher Products, Trinity Tanks, USA, Equimeter, USA, Suregas, South Africa, Oldham France (for Gas Detection Systems), ELSTER Messtechnik GmbH, Germany (for LP Gas metering systems)

Projects solely worked on:

Commercial & Industrial Complexes – Proposed, Designed, installed & commissioned LP Gas Systems for major Clients like

- Buro Happold, Engineer's Office,
- PHB Consultants,
- AMB Building,
- Mott Mac Donald,
- WS Atkins,
- ARTEC,
- Dubai Ruler's Office,
- AFRICON,
- Ssangyong Engineering,
- Arkiteknik Consultants,
- Al Habtoor Engineering,
- Khansaheb Engineering,
- ETA,
- Kharafi National.
- Transgulf Electro Mechanical,
- Emirates Gas.

- EMAAR Properties,
- Hyatt Regency,
- Bilt Middle East,
- Khatib & Alami,
- NORR Group,
- BK Gulf, Everest Kanto Cylinders etc.

Hotel & Resort Projects designed & executed in Dubai

- Madinat Jumeirah Arabian Resorts
- Outlets in Madinat Souq,
- Burj Al Arab,
- Jumeirah Beach Hotel,
- Royal Mirage Resort Phase 1 & 2,
- Dusit Hotel,
- Grand Hyatt Dubai,
- Hyatt Regency (refurbishment),
- Le Meridien,
- Taj Palace Hotel,
- Metropolitan Palace Hotel,
- Al Murooj Complex,
- Outlets in Emirates Tower & Dubai Marina,
- Burj Khalifa Dubai Hotel A &B,

Palace Projects

- Zabeel Palace Kitchen Re-Development Dubai,
- Sheikha Azza Palace in Sharjah,
- Ruler's palace in Sharjah.

Industrial Projects in Dubai /

- JAFZA like EMAAR Gold & Diamond Park,
- Beltexco,
- Cristal Garments,
- EKC Industries,
- Exide Al Dobowi,
- Dabur,
- SRF Overseas,
- Arabian Can Industry,
- Middle East Can,
- Swiss Arabian Perfumery
- Ajmal Perfumes
- Al Tajir Glass,
- Jebel Ali Glass Container,
- Wardah Textiles etc.
- Bottling Plants like Emirates Gas Bottling Dubai,

EMARAT - Dubai

Arrow Energy - Sharjah.

Other Overseas (GCC Countries) Projects:

- Middle East Packaging Industry in Amman, Jordan
- Food processing industries in Oman.

Khodiyar Engineering Works, Mumbai, India (Sept 1993 to Aug 1994)

Specialised in manufacturing of Tools & Moulds for various products.

Trainee - Tool Room Engineer

Responsibilities included

- 1. Designing of Press Tools, Injection moulds, Jigs & Fixtures.
- 2. Distribution of works to related Departments.
- 3. Assembling of the Tools & moulds.
- 4. Trouble shooting & rectification of the problems on trials for the final product.

References

Available on request.

PERSONAL DATA

Date of Birth: 5 January 1974

Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Married

Contact: +91 8904260001 / +91 8149750666

E-mail: cmkamat@hotmail.com
Driving Licence India, UAE & Qatar

OTHER SKILLS

Very good Team player with good communication, interpersonal and presentation skills.

OTHER INTERESTS

Sports: Cricket, Shuttle Badminton, Bowling, Fishing, and Volleyball.

Current Addresses:

Flat C5-402, Provident Welworth City, Yelahanka – Doddaballapur Road, Bangalore – 560064 Karnataka, India

Postal / Permanent Addresses:

'Ashreya', Sai Circle, Lenin Road, Dandeli – 581325 Karnataka, India